Register to The Harold Rome Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Rome, 1935-1981; Series I; 24.2' (58 boxes)
  - Songs, I.B
    - [Dangerous thoughts] Dangerous thoughts / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 396)
      Lyrics ([1] sheet; typescript with pencil additions) laid in
    - [Davy Crockett] Song of Davy Crockett / Music + Lyrics by Harold J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 396)
    - [Death in the afternoon] Death in the afternoon! / Music & Lyrics by Harold J. Rome. -- 1937., 1 manuscript score (10 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 396)
      Pencil note on first p.: written in 1937 Dedicated to Guernica
    - [Declaration] Declaration / Music Harold Rome; Poem by Carl Rakosi. -- 1948 Mar., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 396)
    - [Empty days] Empty days / Harold Rome. -- 1977 Jul. - Aug., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 397)
    - [Fifth philosopher's song] Fifth philosopher's song / Music Harold Rome; Poem Aldous Huxley. -- 1948 Mar. 1., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 397)
    - [Foolish, young and reckless you and I] Foolish, Young and Reckless You and I / Harold Rome. -- 1960 Jul. 22., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 397)
      Includes chord symbols
      Note on first p.: project x
    - [French with tears] French with tears: (with apologies to Edith Piaf) / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 33 cm. (Box 54, Folder 397)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy) with pencil additions
    - [Goldilocks and the three bears] Goldilocks and the three bears / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([14] p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 398)
      Pencil sketch at end
    - [Guilty] Guilty. -- 1970 Jun. 30., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 398)
      Note on folder: Experimental songs June 1970
    - [Guilty] Guilty., 1 manuscript score (4 sheets); 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 398)
    - [Hail Yale '29] Hail Yale '29: (Class Song) / Music + Lyrics H.J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 399)
    - [Hail Yale '29] Hail Yale '29: (Class song) / Music + Lyrics Harold J. Rome., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 399)
      Holograph, signed, in ink and pencil
    - [He's not sick] He's not sick / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 399)
      Note on first p.: Project X
    - [How a French maid's made] How a French Maid's made / Music + Lyrics by J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 399)
    - [I've never met a Yale man before (Sketches)] I've never met a Yale man before / Harold Rome. -- 1966 Feb. 18., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
      With: Waltz Yale man (waltz version) ([2] p.; holograph in pencil)
      Lyrics ([1] sheet; typescript laid in
    - [I keep growing fonder (Sketches)] I Keep Growing Fonder / Harold Rome. -- 1966 Mar. 8., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
      Note: revised version
    - [I never knew] I never knew / Music + Lyrics H.J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
      Note on first p.: Dedicated to F.M.R.
    - [I was in love with George Shapiro] I was in love with George Shapiro / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
    - [I was in love with George Shapiro] I was in love with George Shapiro / Music + Lyrics Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
    - [I was in love with George Shapiro] I Was In Love With George Shapiro / Words and Music by Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
      Note on first p.: NG
    - [If I woke up] If I woke up: (and found myself dreaming) / Music + Lyrics Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 400)
    - [Javits] Javits: campaign song 1962 / Music + Lyrics Harold Rome. -- c1962 Sep. 24., 1 manuscript score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
      Holograph, signed, in pencil on onionskin
    - [Just me] Just me / Harold Rome. -- 1970 Jun. 26., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
      Note on title page: revised
    - [Just me] Just me / Harold Rome. -- 1970 Jun. 24., 1 manuscript score ([2] sheets); 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
    - [Lord Fuichley] Lord Fuichley / Harold J. Rome; Words Hilaire Belloc. -- 1941 Nov., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
      Words in part, interlinear
    - [Love me] Love me, love / Harold Rome. -- 1970 Jun. 7., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
    - [Love me] Love me / Harold Rome. -- [1970?] Jun. 11., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
      Incomplete
    - [Love me (Sketches)] Love me, love / Harold Rome. -- 1970 Jan. 6., [2] p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
    - [Land of might have been (Sketches)] Land of Might Have Been (Sketches) / Harold Rome. -- 1970., [2] p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 401)
      Includes chord symbols Note on folder: Experimental songs June 1970
    - [Marry the bosses' daughter (Sketches)] Marry the Bosses' Daughter / Harold Rome. -- 1960 Sep. 8., [4] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 402)
      Note: Marry (version 3)
      "Bosses Daughter - verse" complete
    - [Mighty diff'rent] Mighty Diff'rent / Music + Lyrics By H.J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 402)
    - [One union] One union!: (A.F.L.-C.I.O.) / Music + Lyrics Harold Rome. -- c1955., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 402)
    - [Red red herring] Red Red Herring / Music + Lyrics by H.J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (10 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 402)
    - [My heart sings; arr.] (All of a Sudden) My heart sings = En Ecoutant Mon Coeur Chanter: For Mixed Chorus (SATB) and Piano / English Lyric Harold Rome; French Lyric by Jamblan; Music by Herpin; Arranged by Gordon Jenkins. -- N.Y.: MCA Music, c1966., 1 chorus score (7 p.); 27 cm. (Box 54, Folder 402)
      Music by "Jamblan" Henri Herpin?
      Pl. no.: 13076-062
    - [My heart sings; arr.] (All Of A Sudden): My heart sings / Words and Music by Harold Rome Jamblan and Herpin; Special Vocal Background by Lou Singer. -- N.Y.: Leeds Music Corporation, c1944., 18 parts; 27 cm. (Box 54, Folder 402)
    - [Small world] Small world / Music and Lyrics Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 33-39 cm. (Box 54, Folder 403)
    - [Song for American union] Song for American union / Music + Lyrics Harold J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (29 sheets); 48 cm. (Box 94)
      For chorus and orchestra
    - [Song for American union; arr.] Song for American union / Music + Lyrics By Harold J. Rome; Poem By Vincent McHugh, 1 manuscript score (14 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 403)
      Arranged for mixed chorus, 2 trumpets, 2 trombones, tympani, snare, and cymbals
      Lyrics (11 sheets; typescript) laid in
    - [Stop walking around in my mind] Stop walking around in my mind! / Music + Lyrics Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 403)
    - [Subversive papa] Subversive papa / Music + Lyrics Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 403)
    - [Sweet love remembered] Sweet love remembered / Harold Rome. -- 1959 Nov. 3., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 403)
      Alternate title, "Just like magic?"
    - [Swing to Stevenson] Swing to Stevenson / Harold Rome. -- 1952 Oct. 24., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 403)
    - [Take your choice] Take your choice / Music + Lyric H.T. [sic] Rome., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
      Words not included in score
      Note at end: copied by Rudolph Burgi-?
    - [Thirteen is a lucky number] Thirteen is a lucky number / Harold Rome. -- c1973., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
    - [Twilight] Twilight / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
    - [Twilight song] Twilight song / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
    - [United Nations; arr.] The United Nations / Music by D. Shostakovitch; Arrangement and words by Harold J. Rome. -- N.Y.: Am-Rus Music Corporation, c1942., 1 score (3 [i.e. 2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
      Arranged for voice and piano
    - [What is a mother for] What is a mother for / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([6] p.); 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
      PHotocopy with pencil markings laid in
    - [Woof camp song] Woof Camp Song / Harold Rome., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
    - [World has become a very small place] The world has become a very small place / Music + Lyrics Harold J. Rome., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 404)
  - Piano Works, I.C
    - [Chaconne sentimentale (Sketches)] Chaconne Sentimentale / Harold J. Rome. -- 1937 Oct., [9] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 405)
    - [Dover beach] Dover Beach., 13 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 405)
    - [Geneva] Geneva: (Satirical Ballet) / Harold J. Rome. -- 1938., 13 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 405)
    - [Inventions, piano] Invention / Harold J. Rome., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 1] Invention., [2] p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
      With: Inventions 2, 4, 5, and 6
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 2] Invention no. 2., [2] p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
      Sketch on back
      With: Inventions 1, 4, 5, and 6
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 4] Invention 4., [1] p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
      With: Inventions 1, 2, 4, and 6
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 5] Invention 5., [2] p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 6] Invention 6., [2] p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
      With: Inventions 1, 2, 4, and 5
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 8] Invention #8 / Harold Rome. -- 1946 Oct., 4 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 10] Invention #10 / Harold Rome. -- 1946 Nov., 3 sheets of music; 28 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
    - [Inventions, piano, no. 11] Invention #11 / Harold Rome. -- 1946 Dec., 4 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 406)
    - [Oh insomnia] Oh Insomnia!: From suite "In America" / Harold J. Rome., 6 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 54, Folder 407)
    - [Passacaglia, piano, E minor (Sketches)] Passacaglia in E min. / H.J. Rome. -- 1937 Mar., [11] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 407)
    - [Piano music. Selections], 1941-1945; [12] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 408)
      Holographs, in part signed, in ink and pencil and manuscript in ink
    - [Piano music. Selections], 1944 Sep.-Dec; 61 p. in various pagings, bound; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 409)
      Contents: Invention #1. Invention #2. Invention #3. Invention #4. Invention #5. Sonatina. Sonatina (2). Essay (in sonata form). Sonata #3.
    - [Piano music. Selections (Sketches)], 1960-1961; [16] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 54, Folder 410)
      Note on folder: old work sheets anonymous compositions
    - [Piano music. Selections (Sketches)], 1975-1976; [102] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 411)
      Note on discarded envelope: Composition Studies 1975-1976
    - [Piano music. Selections (Sketches)], 1976-1977; [30] p. of music, bound; 30 cm. (Box 55, Folder 412)
      Holographs in pencil
      On cover of notebook: Harold Rome Tokyo Jan 76
    - [Snake in the parlor] Snake in the Parlor / By H.J. Rome., [7] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 2] Sonata #2. Harold J. Rome. -- 1944 Oct., 11 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 1] Sonata #1 / Harold J. Rome. -- 1944-1945., 12 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 3] Sonata #3 / Harold J. Rome. -- 1944 Oct.-Nov., 12 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 4] Sonata No. 4 / Harold J. Rome. -- 1944 Oct.-Nov., 13 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 5] Sonata #5 / Harold J. Rome. -- 1944 Dec., [9] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - [Sonatinas, piano, no. 1] Sonatina 1 / Harold J. Rome. -- 1944 Sep., 3 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 414)
      Pencil sketch ([3] p.) laid in
    - [Sonatinas, piano, no. 2] Sonatina 2 / Harold J. Rome. -- 1944 Sep., 4 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 414)
    - [Variations on an unsuspecting theme] Variations on an unsuspecting Theme / By H.J. Rome., 20 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 55, Folder 414)
  - Chamber Music, I.D
    - [String quartet, F major] String quartet in F / Harold J. Rome. -- c1975., 4 manuscript parts; 32 cm. (Box 55, Folder 415-417)
  - Music by Other Composers, I.E
    - [Malady of love. Vocal score] Malady of love: a sham in one act / Music by Lehman Engel; Libretto by Lewis Allan. -- N.Y.: Harold Flammer, Inc., c1954., Engel, Lehman, 1910-1982; 1 vocal score (47 p.); 27 cm. (Box 55, Folder 418)
      Pl. no.: 3111
      Signed by composer
    - [Sonata, violoncello, piano] Sonata for cello and piano / by Lehman Engel. -- N.Y.: G. Schirmer, Inc., c1948., Engel, Lehman, 1910-1982; 1 score (33 p.) + 1 part; 31 cm. (Box 55, Folder 418)
      Publisher's no.: S.P.A.M. 54
- Scripts and Lyrics, 1934-1984; Series II; 8.3' (20 boxes)
  This series includes holograph and typed scripts and lyrics to songs and stage works. They are arranged alphabetically by title, then chronologically. Large groups of miscellaneous scripts and lyrics are at the end. The original order has been maintained to help researchers, since many of the songs appeared in more than one show and it was difficult to determine to which show each lyric belonged. Drafts of letters and production notes are included among these groups, and cross-references from those series have been made. The miscellaneous lyrics include thirteen notebooks arranged chronologically. There are also many lyrics and scripts among the musical sketches.
  Lyrics on legal paper have been photocopied onto acid-free paper, and the originals have been discarded.
  - Author, Author
    - Author, Author, [2], 53, 15 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Typescript with pencil additions
      Includes duplicates
  - Bertha, the Sewing Machine Girl: Or It's Better with a Union Man
    Sketch by Joseph Shrank
    Music by Harold Rome
    - Bertha, the Sewing Machine Girl: Or It's Better with a Union Man, [9] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 2)
      Typescript (photocopy) with pencil additions
  - Bless You All
    Sketches by Arnold Auerbach
    - Bless You All, 5, 6, 8, 5, 5 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 3)
      Typescript
      Includes: Waiter sketch. Restaurant sketch. The cold war. Southern sketch. Hollywood homicide
    - Bless You All, [17] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 3)
      Typescript (copy)
      Originally titled: Love That Man
  - Caleb Catlum's America
    By Valentine Davies and Vincent McHugh from the novel of the same name by Vincent McHugh
    - c1940, [103] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - c1940, 58, 61 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Call Me Mister
    - c1946, 57, 49 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Call Me Mister, [37] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Call Me Mister, [38] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Call Me Mister, [35] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Lyrics
  - Cinderella
    English version of La Cenerentola by Harold Rome
    Done for Billy Rose, never completed
    - Cinderella, [37] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Typescript with pencil and ink additions
  - Destry Rides Again
    Book by Leonard Gershe
    Songs by Harold Rome
    Based on a story by Max Brand
    - Destry Rides Again, 80, 37 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Destry Rides Again, 140 sheets; 30 cm. (Box 56, Folder 8)
      German words
      Typed letter signed (copy) from Ralph Porter dated 1966 Dec. 12 laid in
    - Destry Rides Again, 72, 39 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Destry Rides Again, 73, 40, [5] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 56, Folder 9)
      List of props at end
  - Fanny
    Musical play by Samuel Nathaniel Behrman and Joshua Logan
    Based on the trilogy by Marcel Pagnol
    - c1977, 55, 34 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 57, Folder 10-12)
      Three copies
    - 1984 Mar. 29, 51, 35 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - 1984 May 1, 45, 35 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Giveaways
    - Giveaways, [4] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 57, Folder 15)
      Incomplete, Finale V only?
  - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett)
    Books by Kazuo Kikuta and Horton Foote based on the book by Margaret Mitchell
    - 1959 Oct, [48] sheets; 36 cm. (Box 57, Folder 16)
      Typescript (copy) with pencil additions
      Title: Scarlett (outline)
    - 1968, [6], 167 sheets; 33 cm. (Box 57, Folder 17)
      Note on discarded envelope: Original play - Translation from Japanese
    - 1969 Oct. 27, [28] sheets; 26-38 cm. (Box 57, Folder 18)
      Typescript (photocopy) and manuscript in pencil and ink (in part, photocopies)
      Note: Rehearsal lyric translations used by Joe Layton in rehearsals
      Words in English and Japanese
      Schedules laid in
    - 1969 Oct, 89, 66 sheets; 32 cm. (Box 58, Folder 19-20)
      Typescript (photocopy)
      Two copies, one with pencil markings
      Note: 1st rehearsal script; original script
    - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett), 89, 66 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 58, Folder 21)
      Note: original script
    - 1969 Nov. 4, 186, 138 p., bound; 24 cm. (Box 58, Folder 22)
      Printed
      Note: 1st Japanese script
    - 1969 Dec, 79, 68 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - 1971 Jul. 6, 105 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 58, Folder 24)
      Note on discarded folder: First draft
    - 1969, 145 sheets, bound; 30 cm. (Box 59, Folder 25)
      Note: First script sent by Kikuta N.G.
    - 1971-1972, 57, 54 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 59, Folder 26)
      Adaptation by Horton Foote
      Note: Second Draft
    - 1973 Jul. 15, 103 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 59, Folder 27-28)
      Two copies, one with loose sheets of lyrics laid in
    - ca. 1973-1974, 103 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 59, Folder 29)
      Typescript (photocopies) with pencil additions
      Index of musical numbers, notes by Rome, and USA tour schedules laid in
      Found in trunk labeled: Theatre Under the Stars Houston, TX
    - ca. 1976 Jun. 15, 87 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett), [37] sheets; 28-32 cm. (Box 59, Folder 31)
      Typescript and manuscript (in part, photocopies)
      Lyrics and miscellaneous items
    - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett), 79, 68 sheets; 30cm. (Box 60, Folder 32-33)
      Rehearsal script
    - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett), 98 sheets; 31 cm. (Box 60, Folder 34)
      Note: translation of original
      Japanese script for the play
    - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett), [15] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 60, Folder 35)
    - Gone With The Wind (Scarlett), 64 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 60, Folder 36)
      Typescript (photocopy) with ink additions
      Note on discarded folder: Draft Dallas
      Musical notes ([3] sheets) laid in
  - Grosse Valise
    Adapted by Joseph Fields from "La Grosse Valise"
    Book by Robert Dhery
    Lyrics Andre Maheux and Harold Rome
    Music Gerard Calvi
    - 1963 Sep. 27, 50, 34 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 60, Folder 37)
      Pencil note by Rome laid in
      Note: Second draft
    - Grosse Valise, 48, 30 sheets, bound; 27 cm. (Box 60, Folder 38)
      Notes by Rome and additional sheets laid in
    - Grosse Valise, 37 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 60, Folder 39)
      Act I only
    - Grosse Valise, [15] sheets; 28-32 cm. (Box 60, Folder 40)
      Typescript and holograph in pencil
  - Harold Rome
    - Harold Rome, [17] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 41)
      Lyrics and sheets with musical numbers labeled: Program - Harold Rome
  - Harold Rome at the "Y"
    - 1973 Mar. 11, [24] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 42)
      Typescript with ink additions
      Title and date from discarded folder
      Sheets with "tentative running order" headed: Lyrics and Lyricists series "An Evening with Harold Rome" Sunday, 3/11 & Tuesday, 3/13/73
  - Howe and Hummel
    Book by Joseph Heller
    Jerome Weidman
    - 1963-1964, ca. 150 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 43)
      Additional sheets laid in
    - 1965 Jan.-Mar, ca. 126 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 44)
      Lyrics ([57] sheets; typescript with pencil additions) laid in
    - 1964-1965, ca. 82 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 45)
      Synopsis and additional sheets laid in
    - 1965 Mar. 15?, ca. 119 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 46)
      Date crossed out
    - Howe and Hummel, [17] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 47)
      Miscellaneous lyrics
  - I Can Get It for You Wholesale
    Musical play by Harold Rome and Jerome Weidman
    Book by Jerome Weidman based on his novel of the same name
    - 1961 Oct. 15, 66, 42 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 61, Folder 48)
    - c1962, 120 p.; 21 cm. (Box 61, Folder 49)
      N.Y.: Random House
  - In the Pink
    Book by Moss Hart
    Don Ettinger?
    - 1968 Jan. 7, [65] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 50)
      Envelope from Ettinger with notes by Rome and envelope addressed to Joseph Heller laid in
    - 1968 Jan. 23, ca. 103 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 51)
      Note: First draft
    - In the Pink, [65] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 52-53)
      Note: 1st final draft version Act I
    - In the Pink, 65, 33 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 54)
    - In the Pink, [63] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 55)
      Note: Act I 1st draft
    - In the Pink, [63] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 56)
      Note: 1st draft revised Act I
    - In the Pink, ca. 63 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 57)
    - In the Pink, 55 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 58)
      Note: 2nd draft Act I
    - In the Pink, 55 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 62, Folder 59)
    - In the Pink, 64, 35 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 60-61)
      Typescript and copy
    - In the Pink, 57, 35 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 62)
    - In the Pink, 54, 36 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 64)
      Note: complete revised 1st Act
    - In the Pink, 55 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 65-66)
    - In the Pink, [72] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 67)
      Typescript with pencil additions Act II
    - In the Pink, [20] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 68)
    - In the Pink, 17 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 63, Folder 69)
    - In the Pink, [1] sheet; 32 cm. (Box 63, Folder 70)
  - Jonathan Wild
    Novel by Henry Fielding
    Book by Edward Mann, Maurice Scofield, and Joshua Logan
    Music by Lalo Schifrin
    Lyrics by Harold Rome
    - 1971 Apr.-Sep, [69] sheets; 32 cm (Box 64, Folder 71)
      Sketches for lyrics
      Originally with work sheets for "Engaged"
    - Jonathan Wild, 65, 38 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 64, Folder 72)
      Title: Jonathan the Great
    - Jonathan Wild, 51, 21 sheets; 30 cm. (Box 64, Folder 73)
      Additional pages at end
    - Jonathan Wild, [2] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 64, Folder 74)
  - Little Dog Laughed
    Play by Joseph Schrank
    - c1939, 57, 41 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 64, Folder 75)
      Typed letter signed (copy) from Bernice Foyer to Cheryl Crawford, 1941 May 21, laid in
  - Man and Wife
    An operetta entertainment in six scenes and four commercials by Harold Rome
    - Man and Wife, 21 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 64, Folder 76)
      Synopsis laid in found with "On Borrowed Time" sketches
  - Mr. Brink
    - 1964 Jun. 19, [32] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 64, Folder 77)
      On title page: This booklet contains two copies each of the altered pages of Mr. Brink
    - Mr. Brink, [4] sheets; 28-32 cm. (Box 64, Folder 77)
      Holograph in pencil and typescript with ink additions
      Part of script and sketches for lyrics
    - Mr. Brink, 50, 60 sheets; 28-32 cm. (Box 64, Folder 78)
      Typescript with pencil additions and holograph in pencil
  - Nantucket
    By Samuel Hoffenstein and Gottfried Reinhardt
    Based on an idea by Charles O'Neill
    Music by Vernon Duke